Let's see if you can understand me if I
talk at normal speed. I'm sure most of
you have already watched uh some of my
videos in which I speak a little bit
slower. They're made for people that
can't quite understand native English
yet, and so they need content that's uh
slower, that's a little bit clearer for
them. So, I decided to make uh this
video in which I just talk as if I were
talking to another person like here in
my country in the US, if I were just
talking to a friend or something like
that. Uh, and so I want to uh make this
video and you can use it to see uh if
you can understand me without reading
the subtitles or maybe you can
understand me while you're reading the
subtitles. Doesn't really matter. It's
just uh a way for you to test your
level. And people ask me all the time to
make uh more advanced content. And so
I'm going to talk about that in just a
second. But um here, this video right
here is me just talking normally. And so
you can treat this kind of like a test
just to see where you're at. And if you
end up needing to use the subtitles,
that's perfectly fine. Uh you're just
trying to see uh how much you can
understand uh when I just talk at normal
speed. Um because it's good to kind of
gauge your level from time to time and
see how much you can understand of a
native speaker when they just talk
normally. So uh let me just say that.
And by the way, uh, excuse the
sunglasses and the fact that the sun's
right in my face, but it's freezing
right now. It's not freezing, but I'm a
big baby when it comes to cold weather.
And the season is definitely uh
changing. It's autumn now, and so uh I
kind of want to be in the sun. So that's
why I'm right here with my glasses on.
Excuse the kind of ridiculous look, but
I'm sure you don't mind. So, in general,
I'm easier to understand than most other
native speakers are. And some people
would say I'm the easiest person to
understand. I've had people tell me that
literally I'm the easiest person on the
face of the earth for them to understand
in English. Of course, I'm talking about
uh non-native English speakers, learners
who are trying to learn English. They'll
tell me that I'm the only one they can
understand. I'm the easiest person. I've
always spoken more clearly than other
people. Even before I was an English
teacher. So, it's not just because I'm a
teacher or just because I make this
content. In general, I'm a clear
speaker. I've always been kind of a
storyteller. I've always loved telling
stories and uh just um you know, talking
about things in an animated way and
recounting things uh from the past. Uh
my friends would used to tell me that I
was a good storyteller. Uh I'm a little
bit more dramatic in the way that I
speak than other people perhaps. And I
don't I don't normally speak that fast.
Uh it's just not um normal for me to,
you know, talk super super fast like
that. Uh and so uh I just I'm a little
bit easier for people to understand,
let's say. So, if you can understand me
right now, me talking at normal speed,
uh that doesn't mean that you're going
to be able to understand every other
native English speaker when they talk at
normal speed. So, I just wanted to make
that note. And so, usually because I'm
better uh sorry, I'm uh easier for
people to understand uh because of that
uh people like to use my content as kind
of like an introduction to native
English. So that's why people use like
my advanced podcast episodes, uh even my
US Conversations podcast, people use
those things because uh when I talk at
normal speed, they can still understand
me better than other native speakers.
And so it's kind of like an intermediate
step uh in between like listening to
slower content and listening to just
random native speakers talking. you
know, me talking at normal speed is
usually kind of like one step in between
there just because I'm easier for people
to understand. So that kind of helps
bridge the gap between uh like uh
content made for learners and then
authentic content. So um that's a reason
one of the reasons why people like my
fast content, my advanced episodes, my
US conversations podcast. And you might
uh be watching this video and you're at
a lower level of listening and that's
perfectly fine. You might still be at a
level where uh slower content is
necessary and that's great. You just use
that content and work your way up until
you can eventually use content uh in
which I'm speaking at normal speed or
another native speaker is speaking at
normal speed. It's just like a matter of
getting a little bit better, a little
bit more comfortable um every day and
using content that's appropriate for
your level. And so, um let me talk about
content appropriate for your level. Like
in the comment section of every single
video, I'm sure maybe even in this video
uh under this video, you'll see comments
uh like this as well. Uh, let me address
the questions about people uh that
people ask about B1 videos, B2 videos or
whatever C1 videos. So, I've talked
about this before and I I'll mention
this again. So, you have probably seen
that I make a lot of A1 videos, A2
videos. And the way that I make those
videos is it's not that an A1 video
contains content that is uh you know
perfectly understandable for everyone at
an A1 level. That's not how I classify
an A1 listening practice video because
uh in my opinion when you're at a
certain level and you want to reach the
next level, you have to use content that
is at that next level. you have to
challenge yourself with content that's a
little bit harder for you, a little bit
uh you don't understand everything,
right? And so if you're at an A1 level
and you're listening to a video that's
titled A1 listening practice and that
video just contains language that you
understand perfectly, that's not that
good of practice. I mean, sure, it it's
good to listen to anything, but that's
not necessarily helping you reach the
next level. So, when I title a video A1
English listening practice, just know
that there's uh content in there or the
whole video itself might be above an A1
level, but that's the content that you
should be using if you're at an A1 level
because you should be listening to
content that's a little bit challenging
for you. So, I know some people have
mentioned that in the past like, "Oh,
this is an A1. This is, you know, harder
than that." I know it is. That's the
whole point is that if you're at an A1,
the listening practice videos you should
be using are videos that are above an A1
level. Does that make sense? So, same
thing with A2, right? So, let me address
the B1 question cuz people, you know,
constantly comment this B1, B1, B1. If
you are truly at a B1 level, if you're
at an intermediate level, because B1 is
what? Intermediate. If you're at an
intermediate level, in my opinion, you
should be using content that is made for
native speakers. Or if that's still a
little bit too hard for you, use content
like mine where it's like my advanced
content, advanced podcast where it's at
normal speed, but there's like the
transcript uh there to help you. And you
know, obviously I'm a little bit easier
to understand, but it's basically native
content, but with some tools to help you
understand it. Or like my US
Conversations podcast, it's native
content. we speak normally, but there's
the tool of the transcript with the
definitions of words and phrases that
helps you understand that native
content. If you're at a B1 level, do not
seek uh intermediate level um you know,
podcasts and YouTube videos if you truly
want to reach the next level. I'm not
saying it's bad to do this, but what you
should be doing is you should be using
native content as quickly, as soon as
you can. Not too soon, but I mean as
soon as it's suitable for you. Okay. So,
once I reach a B1 level in Greek, you
better bet that I'm forgetting all the
learner content. I'm not going to use
any more content that's made for
learners at B2. At B1, no, I'm just
going to use native content and
hopefully have tools that can help me
understand that. or I might use a
podcast made by a Greek teacher, but uh
they're speaking at normal speed and
they provide the transcript or something
like that. So, you know, I'm not going
to make B1 and B2 videos and title them
B1 B2 cuz that goes against my
philosophy cuz I think if you're at a B1
level, you should be trying to use
native content. Like this video right
now is a B1 video for you. I'm not
saying that this content is B1. Of
course, I'm just speaking like a native
speaker, but if you're at a B1 level,
this is the type of content you should
be using. It has the subtitles, so it
helps you understand me as I'm talking.
So, B1 should basically just be native
content that has something that helps
you understand it, like subtitles, uh, a
transcript, definitions, things like
that. Uh, or you can just try it without
those things. So, I want to address that
cuz I get that question all the time.
So, if you're asking for B1 videos, that
means you need to start using content
like this. Use native content. Okay. Um,
let me see what else here that I wanted
to talk about. So, uh, okay. Yeah, if if
you're you insist and you say, "No,
Connor, I really want you to make B1
level content, B2 level content." Uh,
well, number one, I just explained to
you this is B1 content. It's just
literally me talking at normal speed. If
that's what you're looking for, use my
advanced episodes because this is what I
do. And in my in my advanced episodes, I
talk like I try to talk even faster
because I know that I speak uh slowly
compared to other speakers. And so uh if
I'm trying to help you get accustomed to
like other people speaking, you know, I
kind of want to speed up my speech a
little bit. So in some of those advanced
episodes, I might talk a little bit
faster at points than I would normally
talk just to kind of get you accustomed
to fast English. Even right now, uh, I'm
trying to fight the urge to speak slower
because I'm someone that generally
doesn't speak that fast. So, I'm trying
to keep the rhythm up. But for me, it's
just not not, you know, that normal for
me to talk fast. Uh, so if you want, if
you're just insisting on having B1 level
content, just use my advanced episodes,
okay? Click on the link in the
description, sign up for those. It's
super cheap. You, once you sign up, you
get all of my advanced episodes from the
past. you're getting dozens and dozens
and dozens and dozens of advanced
episodes with the transcripts. So, it's
a great deal. It's super uh just
convenient. It's my voice. It's the
transcript that you have. So, it's
exactly what you're looking for. And
then, you know, aside from that, the US
Conversations podcast that I talk about
a lot is great as well. If you're
looking for B1 content, B2 content, C1
content, that's you should be using
native level content. And specifically,
if you're asking for like B2 content, C1
content, you should be listening to a
podcast like my US Conversations podcast
in which I talk to another person. So,
you're actually listening to two people
talk and not just one. And then, of
course, I provide the transcript. I give
you the definitions of keywords and
phrases we use. So, that if you're
asking me for that content, I already
make it, okay? You just have to sign up
for it, right? It's just not the free
content that I give here on YouTube.
Because let me just be perfectly honest
with you on YouTube uh you know the
content that most people want just like
the average person who's learning
English on YouTube they're usually
looking for lower level content and so
that's what I make. Okay. So when people
reach a higher level and they need
content that's not just like learner
content you know this is what I offer
you know for my membership and my US
conversations podcast. I reserve that
for for those uh memberships, right?
What I make here for free on YouTube is
the content that most people are looking
for. And you might think, "No, no,
people are looking for higher content."
No, trust me, I I I do this I do this
for a living. And I can tell you that
there's a big difference in view count
uh for like the lower level videos and
the higher level videos. The lower level
videos always consistently uh on average
have more views. Okay? It's because
people are looking for this content on
YouTube. Uh because once you reach a
higher level, you can just start using
native level content. And that's why I
don't release a lot of that content here
on YouTube because I already released
that uh guided native level content, you
know, through my membership, US
Conversations Podcast, etc. So, I really
just want to clear that up. And I know
some of you disagree with me on that.
That's fine. But just know that that's
kind of my model here. This content on
YouTube and my normal podcast is a
little bit lower level content
generally. Um, and then the more guided
higher level content is um, accessible
via my membership, my US Conversations
podcast. But I will probably make videos
like this from time to time where I just
kind of like talk normally. Uh, but it's
not going to be like an every week type
of thing, right? I might do A1 videos,
A2 videos, and then this will be like
the B1 video. So, if you're really
looking for that, you know, I might
release a video like this, but it's not
going to be very often. It's going to be
once every couple months or something
like that. Uh, and so if you really
want, you know, just a lot of content
for that level, uh, please click on the
links down below. And then lastly, let
me just talk about the purpose of
listening. You know, why uh just in
general, why you should do listening
practice, what you're doing it for. So,
number one, you're learning words when
you listen. Okay? And you can do this
with content of any at any level, right?
So you can learn new words from beginner
content because sometimes there are
words that you don't know, right? So
it's still beneficial to listen or uh
listen to or watch any type of content
if you're um you know focused on
learning vocabulary, right? Um, you also
improve your speaking when you listen uh
to pretty much any level content because
as long as it's correct English, you're
kind of internalizing some of the
patterns, some of the things that you
hear in those videos, uh, you copy
native speakers when they talk. Uh, even
like in my lower level videos, you can
copy the sentence structures that I use.
And, uh, once you hear them over and
over again, they just become natural for
you to use. you kind of get a feel for
things, you know, grammar, uh, you know,
different structures. And of course, you
can use repetition, uh, with those
things and just, you know, once you
listen to that same, uh, piece of
content again and again, you're just
going to want to say things that you
hear in that content. So, it helps you
improve your speaking. And then number
three, so vocabulary, speaking, and then
listening. So obviously listening helps
you listen, but specifically like I
mentioned before, if your goal is to
improve your listening, all right, I
want to kind of end on this idea. What I
already mentioned before, you you have
to listen to content that's harder than
just the level where you're at. If you
just listen to content at the level
where you're at, yeah, you're going to
learn words. It's going to help your
speaking. That's all great. That's
beneficial. But if your goal is to
understand better, then you have to use
content that's a little bit challenging
for you. Okay? That's why I do the
videos the way I do them. That's why I
make them this way. If it says A1, it's
not just A1 content. It's harder than
A1, so that you can actually practice
with something that's challenging for
you to reach that next level, right? So,
if you're at a B1 level again and your
goal is to practice your listening,
right? you really want to get better at
listening, you have to listen to
something that's a little bit above your
level. So, if you're at a B1 level, use
guided native content like I already
mentioned. So, if you're looking for
content that uh will help you uh improve
your listening and you're already more
at an intermediate level, then make sure
to click on the links down below uh for
my more advanced content and uh those
will be great for you to help you uh
achieve your listening goals. Okay. All
right. Thank you all for watching this
video and I'll talk to you in the next